Raymond Pearl Papers ca.1895-1940 Mss.B.P312
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Ringrose, Hyacinthe (Box 23)
  - Ritchie, Albert C. (Box 23)
  - Ritter, William E. (Box 23)
  - Roberts, Morley (Box 23)
  - Robinson, Canby (Box 23)
  - Robinson, David M. (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1930-1936; 2 folders (55 items) (Box 23)
    Jones, Lauder W.
    O'Brien, F. P.
    Tisdale, W. E.
    Hanson, F. B.
    Grant, John B.
    Russell, F. F.
    Carter, W. S.
    Flexner, Simon
    Mason, Max
    Smith, Edric B.
    Dean, Rollin C.
    Osterhout, W. J. V.
    Gregg, Alan
    Wesep, H. B. van
    Hackett, Lewis W.
    Weaver, Warren
    Business; Fellowships, assistantships; Recommendations; Russian politics and science
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1931-1934; 2 folders (74 items) (Box 23)
    TenBroeck, Carl
    Robertson, Albert D.
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Editorial matters; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Publication; Research support; Reviews -- Gowen, John W.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Roemer, Th. (Box 23)
  - Rogers, Louis A. (Box 23)
  - Rolleston, Sir Humphry (Box 23)
    Kennedy, Gilbert F.
  - Rolph, George M. (Box 23)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas (Box 23)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 23)
  - Root, Theophilus H. (Box 23)
  - Rose, R. Contee (Box 23)
  - Ross, Frank A. (Box 23)
  - Rous, Peyton (Box 23)
  - Rowe, R. H. (Box 23)
  - Royal Society of Arts (Box 23)
  - Royal Society of Medicine (Box 23)
  - Royal Statistical Society (Box 23)
  - Royster, L. T. (Box 23)
  - Rugg, Harold G. (Box 23)
    Goodrich, Nathaniel L.
  - Ruhland, George C. (Box 23)
  - Russell, A. J. H. (Box 23)
  - Russell, Sir E. John (Box 23)
  - Russell, Edward Stuart, 1934-1944; 64 items (Box 23)
    Biographical and personal data; Displaced German scholars; Educational matters; Evolution; Genetics; Meyer, Adolf; Philosophy of science; Poetry and literature; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Wheeler, William Morton; World War II -- Impact on science; Zoology -- Animal behavior
  - Russell, Walter (Box 23)
  - Ruthven, Alexander G. (Box 23)
  - Sabin, Florence Rena (Box 23)
  - Saint John's College, 1928-1936; 7 folders (229 items) (Box 23)
    Buck, Walter H.
    Melvin, Ridgely P.
    Gordon, Douglas H.
    Meade, Arthur C.
    Cummins, Charles A.
    Noble, Herbert
    Strange, Miriam
    McLaren, Myron
    Stromeyer, William F.
    Campbell, W. W.
    Claggett, T. West
    Scofield, Richard
    Warfield, Edwin, Jr.
    Harrison, Evelyn A.
    Parsly, E. G.
    Hutchins, A. F.
    Appel, Fred W.
    Ebaugh, Lulu V.
    Tydings, Senator Millard E.
    Woodcock, Amos W. W.
    Bingley, George A.
    Rosinger, Kirk E.
    Academic freedom; Committee activities; Educational matters; Fellowships, assistantships; Honors -- Chinard, Gilbert; Honors -- Pearl, Raymond; Research support
  - Salaman, Redcliffe (Box 24)
  - Sanger, Margaret, 1921-1935; 12 folders (390 items) (Box 24)
    American Birth Control League
    Rublee, Juliet Barrett
    Mohr, Otto L.
    Mudd, Stuart
    Stone, Hannah M.
    Dickinson, Robert L.
    Garrett, Robert
    Hooker, D. R.
    Williams, J. Whitridge
    Birth Control League of Delaware
    Fairchild, Henry Pratt
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Political issues; Political issues -- Birth control; Political issues -- Sterilization; Population, demography; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution
  - Sargent, Porter (Box 24)
  - Sargeant, Sara Ward (Box 24)
  - Saturday Evening Post (Box 24)
  - Saunders, P. H. (Box 24)
  - Saunders, Paul A. (Box 24)
  - Schaffner, B. F. (Box 24)
  - Scheltema, A. M. P. A. (Box 24)
  - Schieffelin, Barbara (Box 24)
  - Scgkinivutzm B. H. (Box 24)
  - Schmalhausen, I. (Box 24)
  - Schmalhausen, Samuel D. (Box 24)
  - Schmidt, Peter (Box 24)
  - Schonwetter, M. (Box 24)
  - Schultz, Henry (Box 24)
    Ross, Frank A.
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln (Box 24)
  - Schweizerbart'sche Verlagsbuchhandlung (Box 24)
  - Scientia (Box 24)
  - Seashore, C. E. (Box 24)
  - Segall, J. B. (Box 24)
  - Seligmann, C. G. (Box 24)
  - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley (Box 24)
  - Sewall, Henry (Box 24)
  - Seymour, Mrs. J. H. (Box 24)
  - Shapovalov, Michael (Box 24)
    Jones, L. R.
  - Shaw, Wilfred B. (Box 24)
  - Sherman, M. S. (Box 24)
  - Sherzer, Prof. (Box 25)
  - Shipley, Maynard (Box 25)
  - Shriver, Alfred Jenkins (Box 25)
    White, W. R.
  - Shufeldt, R.W. (Box 25)
  - Shull, George Harrison (Box 25)
    Genetics (Magazine)
  - Sidlo, Thomas L. (Box 25)
  - Siegfried, Andre (Box 25)
  - Sieglinger, John B. (Box 25)
  - Sigerfoos, Charles P. (Box 25)
  - Sigerist, Henry E. (Box 25)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 25)
    Long, J. S.
    Travis, LeRoy O.
    Billinger, R. D.
  - Simon, Charles E. (Box 25)
  - Simpson, George Gaylord (Box 25)
  - Simpson, John S. (Box 25)
  - Singer, Charles (Box 25)
  - Sixteen West Hamilton Street (Box 25)
  - Skinner, Edward R. (Box 25)
  - Sloan, Sam (Box 25)
  - Slosson, Edwin E. (Box 25)
  - Smallwood, William Martin (Box 25)
  - Smith, Barry C. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Frank R., Jr. (Box 25)
  - Smith, H. C. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Ira M. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Hugh M. (Box 25)
  - Smith, Ruby (Box 25)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 25)
    General note
    Moved to National Academy of Science Folder 1
    Walcott, C. D.
    Abbot, C. G.
  - Snyder, Carl (Box 25)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1928-1930; 5 folders (132 items) (Box 25)
    Allen, Carolyn E.
    Moulton, H. G.
    Woodworth, R. S.
    Young, Allyn A.
    Lynd, Robert S.
    East, E. M.
    Barrows, Albert L.
    Garvey, Dorothy
    International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems; National Research Council; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Social Science Research Council. Advisory Committee on Population, 1928-1930; 2 folders (36 items) (Box 25)
    Woodbury, Robert M.
    Sharp, Walter R.
    Woodworth, Robert S.
    Netherwood, Helen
    International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems; National Research Council; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Societe de Biotypologie (Box 25)
    Laugier, M. Henri
    Weinberg, D.
  - Societe de Statistique (Box 25)
    Barroil, A.
  - Societe Linneene de Lyon (Box 25)
    Niced, M. P.
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine (Box 25)
    Goldforb, A. J.
    DeGrange, McQuilken
    Willey, Malcolm M.
  - Society for Promoting Mutual Friendly Relations between Russia and America (Box 25)
    Pohitonoff, W.
  - Society of American Foresters (Box 25)
    Stuart, R. Y.
  - Sokoloff, Boris (Box 25)
  - Solter, George A. (Box 25)
  - Soper, Fred L. (Box 25)
  - Soper, George A. (Box 25)
  - Sorensen, S. P. L. (Box 25)
  - Southern Maryland Society (Box 25)
  - Souza, G. H. DePaula (Box 25)
  - Spear, B. E. (Box 25)
  - Spencer, Clara J. (Box 25)
  - Spilman, Helene Childaux (Box 25)
  - Sprigge, Squire (Box 25)
  - Spring-Rice, Margareth (Box 25)
  - Stahley, E. D. (Box 25)
  - Stanley (Box 25)
  - Standard Oil Company (Box 25)
  - Stanley-Gardner, I. (Box 25)
  - Stanton, E. MacD. (Box 25)
  - Stark, Francis Raymond (Box 25)
  - Starling, Ernest H. (Box 25)
    Carter, L. H.
  - Starling, Florence (Box 25)
  - Stayton, W. H. (Box 25)
    Repeal Associates
    Rich, E. G.
    Rubenstein, Charles A.
    Randall, Blanchard, Jr.
    Rawls, W. Lee
    Carey, James, 3rd
    Livingston, E.
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1919-1939; 10 folders (299 items) (Box 26)
    Bainbridge, William Seaman
    Desbarats, G. J.
    Hinks, Arthur R.
    Moulton, C. Robert
    Frank, Glenn
    Thomas, Charles C.
    Kennedy, Sinclair
    DuBois, Eugene F.
    Blayley, James Roy
    Aeronautics; Anthropology; Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Climate -- Arctic Ocean; Committee activities; Educational matters; Honors; Human genetics; Medical research; Physiology; Publication; Research support; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Steggerda, Morris (Box 26)
    Bush, Vannevar
  - Stephan, Frederick F. (Box 26)
  - Stevens, Henry J. (Box 26)
  - Stevenson, Paul H. (Box 26)
  - Stevenson, T. H. C. (Box 26)
  - Stewart, Mary B. (Box 26)
  - Stewart, Walter W. (Box 26)
  - Stirling, M. W. (Box 26)
  - Stirling, William (Box 26)
  - Stockard, Charles R. (Box 26)
  - Stocks, Percy (Box 26)
  - Stoddard, Lothrop (Box 26)
  - Stoeckel, Robins Battell (Box 26)
  - Stokes, Muriel (Box 26)
  - Stokes, Richard L. (Box 26)
  - Stopes, Marie C. (Box 26)
  - Stout, Wesley Winans (Box 26)
  - Straus, Herbert N. (Box 26)
  - Strauss, Lewis H. (Box 26)
  - Strecker, Edward A. (Box 26)
  - Streisand, Hugo (Box 26)
  - Strong, R. M. (Box 26)
  - Strong, Richard P. (Box 26)
  - Strube, Gustav (Box 26)
  - Summer, F. B. (Box 26)
  - Sumner, Walter Taylor (Box 26)
  - Sundwall, John (Box 26)
  - Surface, Frank M., 1910-1923; 2 folders (51 items) (Box 26)
    Sand, G.
    Simpson, Sutherland
    Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station; Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; Medical research; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Food Administration
  - Survey (Magazine) (Box 26)
  - Sutton, Alan C. (Box 26)
    Stevens, Louise
  - Sweeney, James Shirley, 1923-1932; 67 items (Box 26)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Johns Hopkins University; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Medical research; Publication; Teaching
  - Sweet, Louis D. (Box 26)
  - Swift, Donald S. (Box 26)
  - Swift, Fletcher Harper (Box 26)
  - Sydenstricker, Edgar (Box 26)
    Collins, Selwyn D.
    Britten, Rollo H.
  - Symington, Mrs. Donald (Box 26)
  - Szabo, Istvan (Box 26)
  - Szabo, Margit (Box 26)
  - Tattersall, W. M. (Box 27)
  - Taylor, Griffith (Box 27)
  - Taylor, Henry Osborn (Box 27)
  - Taylor, J. Madison (Box 27)
  - Taylor, Norah B. (Box 27)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America (Box 27)
  - Tedin, Olof (Box 27)
  - Teg, William (Box 27)
  - Terao, Arata (Box 27)
  - Terroine, Emile F. (Box 27)
  - Thayer, Fred I. (Box 27)
  - Thayer, William S. (Box 27)
  - Theis, Louise Morgan (Box 27)
  - Thieme, Georg (Box 27)
  - Thies, Elisabeth S. (Box 27)
  - Thile, Oho (Box 27)
  - Thing, Alice (Box 27)
  - Thomas, Arthur H., Company (Box 27)
  - Thomas, Charles C., 1927-1932; 5 folders (156 items) (Box 27)
    Thomas, N. Payne
    Biographical and personal data; Business -- Williams and Wilkins Company; Editorial matters -- Human Biology; Editorial matters -- Quarterly Review of Biology; Publication
  - Thomas, Paul B. (Box 27)
  - Thomas, William S. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Agnes M. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, C. Fred (Box 27)
  - Thompson, D'Arcy W. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, J. Walter (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Mrs. James R. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Nell (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Richard J. C. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Robert J. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Stewart G. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Warren S. (Box 27)
  - Thompson, Willard C. (Box 27)
  - Thorndike, Edward L. (Box 27)
  - Thurstone, L. L. (Box 27)
  - Time (Magazine) (Box 27)
  - Tinker, E. L. (Box 27)
  - Titcomb, W. P. (Box 27)
  - Todd, T. Wingate (Box 27)
  - Tomanek, Ewald (Box 27)
  - Tomlinson, Paul G. (Box 27)
  - Torovsky, Adolph (Box 27)
  - True, A. C. (Box 27)
  - Tucker, William B. (Box 27)
  - Tucker, W. J. (Box 27)
  - Turner, F. M. (Box 27)
  - Tydings, Millard (Box 27)
  - U.S. Army Adjutant General (Box 27)
  - U.S. Census office (Box 27)
  - U.S. Customs (Box 27)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 27)
  - U.S. Department of State (Box 27)
    Kotsovsky, B. A.
  - U.S. Railroad Administration (Box 27)
  - Universita Cattolica del Sacro Cuore (Box 27)
  - University of Adelaide (Box 27)
  - University of Chicago (Box 27)
    Schuman, Frederick L.
  - University of London (Box 27)
    Bell, Julia
    Uhaze, Margaret
    Deller, Edwin
    James, J. K.
    Murrell, W. Stanley
  - University of Michigan, 1932-1939; 2 folders (Box 27)
    Tapping, T. Hawley
    Shaw, Wilfred B.
    Rutheven, Alexander G.
    Walton, Ivan H.
    Burklund, Carl E.
    - Folder 1, 1932-1939 (Box 27)
    - Folder 2 -- 1937 Celebration (Box 27)
  - University of Michigan. Alumni Association (Box 27)
    Johnson, A. Esther
  - University of Texas (Box 27)
  - University of Wisconsin Press (Box 27)
  - Unknowns (Box 27)
  - Upton, Pattee Templetown (Box 27)
  - Van Cleave, H. J. (Box 28)
  - Vavilov, N. I. (Box 28)
  - Van Riper, Walker (Box 28)
  - Varigny, M. H. De (Box 28)
  - Varney, Lucius E. (Box 28)
  - Vaughan, George (Box 28)
  - Vaughan, T. Wayland (Box 28)
  - Vaughan, Victor C. (Box 28)
  - Veblen, Oswald (Box 28)
  - Vermont. Department of Public Health (Box 28)
  - Verschuer, O. von (Box 28)
  - Vial, L. G. (Box 28)
  - Viguin, D. C. (Box 28)
  - Vincent, George E. (Box 28)
  - Vitale, Alfredo (Box 28)
  - Volterra, Virginia (Box 28)
  - Volterra, Vito (Box 28)
    Donnan, F. G.
  - Voorhis, E. (Box 28)
  - Wade, Joseph S. (Box 28)
  - Wagner, George (Box 28)
  - Walch, Mrs. E. (Box 28)
  - Walcott, F. C. (Box 28)
  - Walcott, Frederic C., 1919-1938; 3 folders (63 items) (Box 28)
    Doyle, Sir Arthur Conan
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Business; Doyle, Arthur Conan, Sir; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific refugees; Solicitations for support or contribution
  - Walker (Box 28)
  - Walker, Fred (Box 28)
  - Walkey, C. E. J. (Box 28)
  - Wallace, Alfred Russel (Box 28)
  - Wallengren, Hans (Box 28)
  - Walsh, James J. (Box 28)
  - Walton, A. C. (Box 28)
  - Walton, James A. (Box 28)
  - Ward, H. B. (Box 28)
  - Wardle, Ed. B. (Box 28)
  - Warner, Stackpole and Bradlee (Box 28)
  - Wartensleben (Box 28)
  - Waterman, J. (Box 28)
  - Watkins, J. E. (Box 28)
  - Watkinson, Grace B. (Box 28)
  - Watson, Herbert L. (Box 28)
  - Watson, John B. (Box 28)
  - Waxter, T. J. S. (Box 28)
  - Weed, Lewis H. (Box 28)
  - Weiskotten, H. G. (Box 28)
  - Welch Memorial Library (Box 28)
  - Welch, William H., 1916-1932; 4 folders (141 items) (Box 28)
    Durham, Louise
    Hatfield, Charles J.
    Farrand, Max
    Storey, T. A.
    Cannon, Walter B.
    Hektoen, L.
    Weed,
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Educational matters; Harvard University; Johns Hopkins University; Medical research; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Political issues; Publication; Recommendations; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Weld, Lewis H. (Box 28)
  - Wells, H. G. (Box 28)
  - Welsh, John H. (Box 28)
  - Wharton, Laurence (Box 28)
  - Wheeler, Dora (Box 28)
  - Wheeler, William Morton, 1910-1937; 7 folders (243 items) (Box 28)
    Includes correspondence pertaining to Pearl's removal to Bussey Institute, Harvard University.
    Henderson, L. J.
    Lowell, A. Lawrence
    James, Henry
    Ants; Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Eugenics; Harvard University -- Bussey Institute; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Political issues; Publication; Publication -- Human Biology; Recommendations; Referee's report; Requests for aid in finding positions; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - White (Box 28)
  - White, E. Grace (Box 28)
  - White, W. Rushmer (Box 28)
  - White, Warner G. (Box 29)
  - White, William A. (Box 29)
  - Whitehead, J. B. (Box 29)
  - Whitman, C. O. (Box 29)
  - Whitman, Ezra B. (Box 29)
  - Whitney, C. A. (Box 29)
  - Whitney, Jessamine S. (Box 29)
  - Whitney, Leon F. (Box 29)
  - Whyte, L. L. (Box 29)
  - Wiegard, Annie Laurie (Box 29)
  - Wiggam, A. E. (Box 29)
  - Wight, Carol (Box 29)
  - Willard, Daniel (Box 29)
  - Willard, Mrs. H. N. (Box 29)
  - Willard, Harley R. (Box 29)
  - Willcox, Walter F., 1922-1940; 5 folders (158 items) (Box 29)
    Bowley, A. L.
    Steuart, W. M.
    Hoover, Herbert
    Zahn, Friedrich
    Pitt-Rivers, Captain
    Stamp, J. C.
    Durand, E. Dana
    Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Displaced German scholars; Johns Hopkins University; Physiology; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Williams, Ira Jewell (Box 29)
    Van Anda, Carr V.
  - Williams, Ira Jewell, Jr., 1925-1941; 7 folders (143 items) (Box 29)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Hitler, Adolph; Human evolution, physical anthropology -- Race; Political issues; Publication; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Williams, Robert (Box 29)
  - Williamson, S. T. (Box 29)
  - Williams and Wilkins Company (Box 29)
  - Willis, J. C. (Box 29)
  - Willoughby, R. R. (Box 29)
  - Wilson, C. B. (Box 29)
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1922-1936; 8 folders (242 items) (Box 29)
    Bowley, Arthur L.
    American Philosophical Society; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Educational matters; Eugenics; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Harvard University; Human genetics; Johns Hopkins University; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Recommendations; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Teaching
  - Wilson, Elizabeth G. (Box 30)
  - Wilson, H. V. (Box 30)
  - Wimpenny, R. S. (Box 30)
  - Winchester, P. (Box 30)
  - Winckel, Max (Box 30)
  - Windisch, J. (Box 30)
  - Wing, Leonard W., 1939; 45 items (Box 30)
    Van Tyne, J.
    Cole, Leon J.
    Ruthven, Alexander S.
    Graves, Henry S.
    Richards, Edward C. M.
    Leopold, Waldo
    Griswold, B. Howard, Jr.
    Battler, W. G.
    Walcott, Frederic C.
    Bell, J. W.
    Barbour, Thomas
    Huntington, Ellsworth
    Bell, James F.
    Baetjer, Edwin G.
    Griswold, B. Howell
    Post, A. H. S.
    Biographical and personal data; Recommendations; Solicitations for support or contribution; Wildlife management
  - Winkelhagen, J. (Box 30)
  - Winslow, C. E. A. (Box 30)
  - Winsor, Agnes (Box 30)
  - Winsor, Charles P., 1926-1936; 66 items (Box 30)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Embryology, developmental genetics; Graduate study; Human genetics; Johns Hopkins University; Population, demography; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Wintrobe, M. M. (Box 30)
  - Wislocki, George B., 1931-1940; 54 items (Box 30)
    Biographical and personal data; Displaced German scholars; Editorial matters; Harvard University; Korzybski, Alfred; Needham, Joseph; Publication
  - Wolf, Georg (Box 30)
  - Wolfenden, Hugh H. (Box 30)
  - Wolfson, Fruma (Box 30)
  - Wood, Robert W. (Box 30)
  - Wood Jones, Frederick (Box 30)
  - Woodger, J. H. (Box 30)
  - Woodruff, Charles E. (Box 30)
  - Woodruff, Mrs. Charles E. (Box 30)
  - Woodruff, L. L. (Box 30)
  - Woods, Alan C. (Box 30)
  - Woods, Charles D., 1906-1925; 5 folders (110 items) (Box 30)
    Houghton, T. E.
    Morse, W. J.
    Curtis, Ellicot D.
    Winslow, C. E. A.
    Winge, Ojvind
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Genetics -- Cattle; Human genetics; Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; Massachusetts Department of Agriculture; National Research Council; Poultry genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; World War I -- Impact on science; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Woods, Francis Carter (Box 30)
  - Woods, Frederick Adams (Box 30)
  - Woodward, Robert S. (Box 30)
  - Woodworth, R. S. (Box 30)
  - Woofter, T. J., Jr. (Box 30)
  - Woollcott, Alexander (Box 30)
  - Woollcott, William (Box 30)
  - Woolcott, Mrs. William (Box 30)
  - Worcester, D. C. (Box 30)
  - World Population Conference (Box 30)
    Chance, Janet
    Spring Rice, Margareth
    Martyn, Edith How
  - Wright, Albert H. (Box 30)
  - Wright, C. P. (Box 30)
  - Wright, Herman P. (Box 30)
  - Wright, Katharine (Box 30)
  - Wright, Quincy (Box 30)
  - Wyld, Norman (Box 30)
  - Wynkoop, Hallenbeck, Crawford Company (Box 30)
  - Yatsu, Naohide (Box 30)
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1903-1929; 86 items (Box 30)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Johns Hopkins University; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Research Council; Publication; Reviews; Solicitations for support or contribution; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Teaching; Zoology -- Animal behavior
  - Yntema, Hessel E. (Box 31)
  - Yoke, Helen A. (Box 31)
  - Young, Allyn A. (Box 31)
  - Young, Hugh H. (Box 31)
  - Yule, Udney (George Udny), 1903-1944; 155 items (Box 31)
    Genetics; Honors; Pearson, Karl; Population, demography; Poultry genetics; Protozoan genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Zeliff, C. Courson (Box 31)
  - Zobell, Claude E. (Box 31)
  - Zucchero, P. J. (Box 31)
- Series II. Ida May Pearl Correspondence, 1895-1934; 2 boxes (138 items) (Box 31-32)
  Personal correspondence between Pearl and his mother.
  Biographical and personal data; Dartmouth College; Educational matters; Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Publication; Travel -- Europe; World War I -- Food Administration
  - Correspondence, 1895 - June 1916 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, June 1916 - 1934, n.d. (Box 32)
- Series III. Maud Pearl Correspondence (Box 32-33)
  Personal correspondence, consisting primarily of letters from her husband, Raymond, but including a small number of letters of family and friends addressed to Maud Pearl.
  - to Maud Pearl, Archbold, Helen (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Archbold, Helen (Box 32)
    Beauty preparations
  - to Maud Pearl, Beckwith, Cora J. (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Benson and Miller (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Bird, J. Malcolm (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Bliss, Leon D. (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Halsbed, W. T. (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Harris, F. K. (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Inglis, William (Box 32)
    DeWitt, Alice
  - to Maud Pearl, Jennings, H. S. (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 32)
  - "List of people invited to the wedding" (Box 32)
  - to Maud Pearl, Parcek, Bertha A. (Box 32)
  - to Raymond Pearl, 1901 June 9 - 1929 June 19; 440 folders; Pearl, Maud Mary DeWitt (Box 32-33)
    Biographical and personal data; Biological Survey of the Great Lakes; Conferences and symposia; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Europe; University of Iowa; University of Michigan; World War I -- Food Administration
    - to Raymond Pearl, 1901 June 9 - 1910 August; Pearl, Maud Mary DeWitt (Box 32)
    - to Raymond Pearl, 1910 December - 1929 June 19; Pearl, Maud Mary DeWitt (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, 1910; 9 folders; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940 (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Pearl, Ruth DeWitt (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Porter, George P. (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Unidentified (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Van Rensselaer, Alexander (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Yule, G. Udny, (George Udny), 1871-1951 (Box 33)
  - to Maud Pearl, Yule, H. R. (Box 33)
- Series IV. Bound Volumes (Box 34-40)